Register of the Namibian subject collection, 1920-2000
Hoover Institution Archives
Namibian Subject Collection,
1920-2000
XX786
7 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 phonorecords, 1 videotape cassette. (3.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, serial issues, flyers, reports, and other printed matter, relating to revolutionary movements in Namibia, especially the South West African Peoples Organisation, and to political, social and economic conditions in Namibia.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
SWAPO.; Namibia--History.; Namibia.; Africa.; Phonorecords.; Video tapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1971-1995. (Boxes 1-3)
  Brochure, bulletins, flyers, leaflets, newsletters, pamphlets, printed matter, reports and serial issues relating to economic, political and social conditions in Namibia
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1965-1995. (Boxes 3-5)
  Brochures, bulletins, clippings, leaflets, newsletters, pamphlets and printed matter relating to revolutionary movements in Namibia
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1991. (Box 5)
  Calendar, flyer and poster relating to Namibia
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1984-1988. (Record cabinet; Tape cabinet)
  Two phonorecords and one videotape cassette relating to the changing environment in Namibia
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after January 1995
- SUBJECT FILE, 1971-1995.
  - General (Box 1)
  - Atrocities
    - Kassinga
    - Oshikuku
  - Economics
    - Domestic
      - General
      - Drought
      - Rvssing Uranium Ltd.
      - Trade unions - Mineworkers Union of Namibia
    - International
      - General
      - Campaign Against the Uranium Contracts
  - Education
    - General
    - Namibia National Students' Organization
    - University of Namibia
  - Foreign relations
    - South Africa
    - United States (Box 2)
      - Congressional hearings
      - Congressional Research Service
  - Health
    - General
    - Acquired Immune Deficiency System (AIDS)
  - International support groups
    - General
    - American Committee on Africa
    - Association of Concerned Africa Scholars (ACAS)
    - Bay Area Namibia Action Group
    - Catholic Institute for International Relations(CIIR)
    - Namibia Emergency Campaign
    - National Namibia Concerns
    - Operation Namibia
    - PROSWA/Namibia Foundation
    - Third World First
    - World Council of Churches
  - Political parties and organizations
    - Demokratic Turnhalle Alliance (DTA)
    - Federal Party (FP)
    - Herstigte Nasionale Party (HNP)
    - Labor Party
    - Namibia National Front (NNF)
    - Namibian Independence Party (NIP)
    - National Party (NP) South Africa
    - National Patriotic Front of Namibia (NPF)
    - Pro-South-West-Africa
    - Republican Party (RP)
    - United Democratic Front of Namibia (UDF)
  - Politics (Box 3)
    - Multi-party conference of South West Africa/Namibia
    - Namibian independence
      - General
      - Constitutional conference, Turnhalle
        - General
        - Reports
      - Elections
      - Resolution 435
- REVOLUTIONARY MOVEMENTS, 1965-1995
  - South West Africa National Union (SWANU) (Box 3)
  - South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO)
    - General
      - General
      - Conference proceedings. Namibia International Conference (Box 4)
      - Declarations and statements
    - Economics
    - Foreign relations
      - Angola
      - Frente de Libertagco de Mocambique (FRELIMO)
      - South Africa
      - United Nations
      - United States
    - Information bulletins
    - International support groups
      - General
      - Namibia Support Committee
      - SWAPO Women's Solidarity Campaign and SWAPO Women's Council
    - Interview with Andreas Shipanga
    - Media
      - Namibia Press Agency
      - Press releases and communiques (Box 5)
    - Political programs and constitution
    - Prisoners
    - Refugees
    - Speeches, statements by, and interviews with, Sam Nujoma
    - Women
  - South West Africa People's Organization Democrats
- MISCELLANEOUS FILE, 1991
  - Calendar (Box 5)
  - Flyer
  - Poster
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1984-1988
  - Phonorecords (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
    - "Onyeka, " The Torch Cultural Group of the South West Africa People's Organization, 1984
    - "Wind of Change, " 1985
  - Videotape cassette. "Namibia the Untold Story, " 1988 (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 6-8:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.